（マダラ）懐かしい風景だ。
This landscape brings back memories...
（カブト）土影と風影は
さすがに　しぶとい。
The Tsuchikage and Kazekage
are especially persistent.
どうしますか？
What should we do?
（サガン）ヤツらだ！　４時の方向！
It's them!
At four o'clock!
（マダラ）木遁　樹界降誕！
Wood Style: Deep Forest Emergence!
（ドダイ）木遁まで…。
He can do Wood Style?!
どうやら　ここまでのようだ…。
I guess this is it for us...
《ナルト：クソ…
チャクラも　もう残り少ねぇ。
Damn it! I don't have
much chakra left!
どうすりゃ…》
What should I do?
（九尾）ナルト　今回は力を貸してやる。
Naruto, this time I'll lend you
my power.
また体をあけわたせって
言いてぇのか？
Are you gonna say you want me to
surrender my body over to you again?!
違う。　チャクラだけをやる。
No...
I'll just give you my chakra.
マダラは好かん。
I don't care for Madara...
アイツに操られるぐらいなら
お前のほうが　ましだ。
If I'm gonna be controlled,
I'd rather it be you than him!
《カブト：このまま　マダラを
うまく利用すれば→
If I can keep using Madara like this,
戦局をコントロールできる。
これほどの手札になるとはね》
I'll be able to control
the tide of this battle.
I didn't expect him to become
a card this strong.
（我愛羅）ナルト！
Naruto!
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
大玉螺旋丸！
Giant Rasengan!
やれ　ナルト！
Do it... Naruto!
大玉螺旋帯連丸！
Giant Rasengan Barrage Line!
お前の言うとおり
なかなかのヤツだ。
As you mentioned, he's quite a guy.
でしょう？
Right?
ハア…　ハア…。
《九尾にもらったチャクラ
一気に使っちまった…。
I used up the chakra Nine Tails
gave me all at once!
もう…　限界だ…。
I'm at my limit!
今にも消えちまいそうだ…》
I'm going to disappear
at any moment!
（オオノキ）ナルト…　もういい。
Naruto... Enough.
あとは　わしらがやる。
I'll take over from here.
（テマリ）土影殿　もう　アンタも…。
Lord Tsuchikage,
you're in the same...
（オオノキ）フン…
やっと己を拾う場がきた。
I finally have a chance
at reclaiming myself!
そのための相手には十分じゃぜ。
And I've got myself a worthy opponent!
softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
The Five Kage Assemble
わしが相手をする。
I'll fight him!
ムチャだって！
もう　ボロボロじゃねえかよ！
That's crazy!
You're in no shape to do it!
ハア…　ハア…　ハア…。
もう少し術を試したいんだが→
I'd like to try out some more jutsu...
もう踊れそうにないな　オオノキよ。
But I don't think
you can dance anymore, Ohnoki.
なんだ？　その顔は。
What's that look?
昔　一度　力の差を
教えてやったはずだが。
Long ago, I showed you
the difference in our strength.
((オオノキ：なぜ…。
Why?
それでは話が違う！　柱間殿は…。
That wasn't the agreement!
（マダラ）同盟などない。
木ノ葉の力の前に　ただ従え。
Lord Hashirama is...
There is no alliance...
Just submit to the power
of the Hidden Leaf!
(それと　俺の前で
その忍の名を口にするな))
And... never mention the name
of that shinobi in front of me!
わしら　忍は
ずっと戦いに明け暮れてきた。
We shinobi are weary
of all this endless fighting.
自国と自里の利益のためだけに
ずっと戦い続け→
We've kept on fighting for
the sake of our nations and villages.
他国と他里など省みず　ただ奪う。
Without a care about other nations
and villages, we just take!
奪っては奪われ
奪われては奪い返す…。
We take away, then they take away
in an endless cycle...!
憎しみは膨れあがり
三度も戦争をした。
Hatred has caused three wars!
それが　生きていくということだ。
That is life.
その歳まで生きて　過去の痛みから
何も学んでいないとはな。
I can't believe
you've lived this long
and not learned a thing
from the pain of the past.
アンタよりは長く生きてる。
I've lived longer than you!
学び　ひと回りした。
I've learned twice as much!
過去の痛みを知るからこそ→
It's because I've experienced pain
in the past
どう　先につなげていくのが
最善かを　考えることができる。
that I can even consider
what would be best for the future!
で…　また　四度目の戦争だ。
Yet this is the fourth war!
これが　最善ですか？
Is this what's best?
この戦争は違う！
This war is different!
かつて　戦争で
奪い合ってきたものとは→
Unlike the past wars where
we took from each other...
別のものを
皆が手に入れるための戦いじゃぜ。
this time, we are fighting together
in order to achieve something different!
（オオノキ）コイツらを見ていて→
By watching them,
時は　ただ刻むだけのものではない
と　わかった。
I've learned that time
does not simply pass by!
世界は過去を重ねて
ゆっくりとだが　成長しておる。
Though slow in pace, the world is
accruing its past experiences...
平和へ向けてのう。
and heading towards "peace."
ハァ　ハァ…。
世界は
これ以上　成長する必要はない。
There's no need for the world
to mature any further.
無限月読の幻術の中で
眠っていればいい。
It can slumber in the genjutsu
of the Eternal Tsukuyomi!
かつて　アンタが　わしに
己を捨てさせた。
Long ago, you made me forsake myself.
じゃから
ここで　アンタに勝ち　己を拾う！
That's why...
I will defeat you here...
and reclaim myself!
眠るのは　アンタじゃぜ！
The one who will slumber shall be you!
（ドダイ）土影殿！
Lord Tsuchikage!
さぁ　一緒に拾うとしよう。
Come... I will help you
reclaim yourself.
年寄りに　若いヤツらが
世話を焼きすぎると→
The elderly always complain
when young ones try to help...
文句を言うのが決まりなんだが。
ハッ！
今回は　おせっかいも認めてやる。
I'll let you all meddle this time!
フッ…　まだ　踊れそうだな。
It seems they can still dance.
己のために　未来のために
お前は　ここで倒す！
For myself!
For the future!
I will bring you down!
（綱手）クソ！
（カツユ）綱手様！
Damn it!
Lady Tsunade!
（綱手）マブイといったな？
天送の術の用意をしろ。　来い！
You said your name was Mabui?
Prepare to do
your Ethereal Transmission Jutsu!
（マブイ）天送の術は
物を送るための術です。
Come with me!
Ethereal Transmission is
a jutsu used to transport items!
口寄せや　逆口寄せと違って
人は　ムリなんです　本来！
Unlike the Summoning
or Reverse Summoning Jutsu,
it's impossible to transport people!
ぐだぐだ言っている暇はない！
There's no time to argue!
Unless we try, we'll never know!
やってみなければ
わからないだろう。
わかります！
I do know!
早すぎる転送に
肉体がついていけず→
The transmission rate is so fast, the body
cannot keep up and will be torn apart.
ズタズタになって　死亡するだけです！
Death is certain!
（マブイ）かつて　この天送の術で
移動できたのは→
The only one who survived
Ethereal Transmission in the past
三代目　雷影様だけです！
is the Third Raikage!
三代目は強靭すぎる肉体が
あったからこそです。
But that was only because
of his superhuman body.
三代目の血を引く
四代目　雷影様なら　ともかく→
Now I can understand the Fourth Raikage
since he is of the Third's blood...
火影様は　まず　ムリです。
お考え直しください。
But Lady Hokage,
it's impossible for you!
Please reconsider this!
（シカク）少し　考えがあります。
飛雷神の術です。
I have an idea...
The Flying Raijin Jutsu.
ゲンマの小隊を　ここに呼び
先に　カツユの１匹にマーキングをつけて→
We'll summon Genma's squad here.
Then if we mark
one of Katsuyu's clones,
現場に天送させれば…。
and transmit her to the site first...
私は　バラバラになっても
平気な能力ですから。
I have the ability to survive
being split into pieces...
必要ない！　私は　これを使う。
That's not necessary!
I will use this.
そういうことですか。
So that's it.
でも　危ない賭けですよ。
But it's a risky gamble.
And you tend to be unlucky with bets...
だいたい　綱手様は
賭けに弱いってのが…。
それは　金を賭けたときだ。
That's only when I bet money.
GAMBLE
命をかけたときは　別だ。
It's different when I bet my life.
That's why I'm still alive.
だから　今まで　生きている。
はぁ…。
雷影様！
火影様に　考え直すようにと…。
Lord Raikage!
Please tell Lady Hokage
to think it over...
（エー）うむ…。
マブイ　天送の準備をしろ。
Mabui, prepare the Ethereal Transmission...
２人分だ。
雷影様まで…。　シカクさん！
For two.
Not you too, Lord Raikage!
状況は　最終段階まできている。
Shikaku!
We have no other options left.
今こそ総大将の出番だ。
It's time for the Supreme Commander
to make his appearance!
うむ。
しかし　マダラは　うちは一族。
However, Madara belongs
to the Uchiha Clan...
火遁をどうにかしなければ
勝ち目はない。
If we don't do something
about the Fire Style,
飛雷神の術は
アイツのために使ってもらう。
we won't have a chance at winning.
We'll use the Flying Raijin Jutsu...
against him.
うお～っ！
クソッ！
Damn!
（長十郎）自身の力　イコール　斬った数。
The more I cut down,
the more confidence I gain.
だから　斬らなきゃ　とにかく…。
That's why I just have to keep slicing!
（メイ）うん。
（ライドウ）おう。
Right!
（ゲンマ）ずいぶんチャクラを
ためてると思ったが→
Yeah!
I thought that was a lot of chakra
he was gathering...
ここまで　でかい剣になるとはね。
But I had no idea the sword
would be this huge...
こ　これでは　動けない。
I-I can't move...
一瞬で　刀の形状を
ここまで変化させるとは…。
I can't believe that you changed
that sword so quickly.
やるじゃねえか　アイツ。
He's pretty good!
《シカク：ゲンマ　悪いが　俺の
言うとおりにしてくれないか》
Genma!
Sorry, but could you please
just do as I say?
シカクさん？
Is that you, Shikaku?
《急を要する事態だ。
It's urgent. Do exactly as I say,
no interruptions!
何を言っても突っ込みはなしだ。
まず　本物のマダラが
穢土転生で復活した。
First off, the real Madara
has been reanimated.
《すみません。
突っ込んでいいですか》
Sorry, but can I interrupt?
《なしだと言ったはずだ》
I said no!
やれ！
いきますよ。
Do it!
H-Here I go...
《天送の術》
Ethereal Transmission Jutsu!
驚いたわね　空間を
一瞬で移動って→
I'm surprised...
Instantaneous travel
through dimensions...
四代目火影の術のはずでしょ。
Isn't that the Fourth Hokage's jutsu?
俺たちは　もともと→
We used to belong to a squad
assigned to protect the Fourth Hokage.
四代目火影を守る
護衛小隊の忍です。
今は　五代目ですが　飛雷神の術は
四代目から教わったものです。
Now, it's the Fifth Hokage, but...
The Flying Raijin Jutsu
was taught to us by the Fourth.
ただし四代目と違って
３人でやらないとできなくて。
But unlike the Fourth,
it takes the three of us for it to work.
窮屈ですみませんね。
We apologize for the tight fit.
水影様　マダラを
ぶっ倒してきてください。
Lady Mizukage...
Please bring Madara down!
ここは　忍刀七人衆の
僕が死守します。
As one of the Seven Ninja
Swords Men of the Mist,
I will protect this place with my life!
長十郎。
《メイ：この子　里を出てから
ずいぶんたくましくなった》
Chojuro...
He's matured so much
since leaving the village.
（ゲンマ）用意を。　綱手様に
マーキングが施してあります。
Please get ready!
Lady Tsunade bears
the Jutsu Formula on her.
綱手様が戦場に着きしだい
我々も飛びます。
The instant she arrives
on the battlefield,
了解よ。　遅れるのは
婚期だけで十分です。
we will make the jump!
Understood!
I'm already late getting to the altar.
I won't be late for anything else.
《きかん坊に　綱手姫か》
Unruly Ay and... Princess Tsunade!
俺が本部に座標を連絡しておいた。
I've relayed our coordinates to HQ!
陰封印　解！　忍法　創造再生！
Reserve Seal! Release!
Ninja Art of Mitotic Regeneration!
大丈夫か。
ああ。
Are you all right?!
綱手のばあちゃん！
Yeah...
Granny Tsunade?!
《これ　再生する術のやつだ》
That's her regenerating jutsu!
うわっ！
皆　まだ生きてるってことは
遅れずに済んだようね。
Since everyone is alive,
I guess we weren't late.
やっと暴れられる。
待ちくたびれたわ。
Finally, I'll get to see some action...
I've been bored stiff!
さぁ　準備はできた。
All right, I'm ready!
やはり
長生きはしてみるもんじゃぜ。
Living long was well worth it.
まさか　五影揃って
ともに戦う日が来るとはな。
Imagine... Being able to see the day
when the Five Kage would be united
and fight side by side.
ちょうどいい。
This is perfect.
これくらいでなければ
試しがいがない。
This will make my test worthwhile.
すまぬ　綱手姫。
Thank you, Princess Tsunade.
２人を回復する。　雷影　水影！
I'll heal the two of you.
Raikage, Mizukage!
Buy me some time!
少しの間　時間稼ぎを頼む。
いくぞ　水影。
はい。
Here we go, Mizukage!
Right!
溶遁　溶怪の術！
Lava Style: Lava Monster Jutsu!
《この程度の術なら
吸い取るまでも…》
Jutsu this pitiful isn't even
worth absorbing!
He's fast!
《速いな》
雷虐水平チョップ！
Lateral Bolt of Pain! Chop!
《こんなとこにいるのが
場違いな気がしてくる》
I feel so out of place here...
（イワシ）やってねえよな　たぶん…。
He's probably not dead yet, huh?
あぁ　辺りをこんなにしたヤツだ。
気を抜くな。
He's capable of this much destruction...
Stay alert!
割って入るタイミングがないぜ。
There's no way for us to jump in.
お前たちは　俺と一緒に
もう一人のほうを狙うぞ。
You guys come with me...
I'm going after the other one.
協力しろ！
Help me!
アイツか！
行くぞ　こい！
Is that him?
Follow me! Let's go!
まだか　火影。
How much longer, Hokage?!
もう少しだ。
Almost done!
綱手のばあちゃん
大丈夫なのか？
Are you okay, Granny Tsunade?
額の印の術使うと
ババアになって　倒れちまうんだろ？
Whenever you use
that forehead mark jutsu,
you get old and fall down!
今回は　ペインのときとは違う。
This is different from
the time with Pain.
自分一人の…　しかも
この程度の傷を治しただけだ。
I only healed myself...
And besides,
it wasn't much of an injury.
まだまだ　チャクラはたっぷりある。
I have more than enough chakra!
それじゃあ
俺も回復を頼むってばよ。
Then heal me too!
分身であっても
まだ消えるわけにはいかねえ。
I may be a clone,
but I can't afford to disappear yet!
ここで俺も…。
その必要はない。
I'll join you and...
That's not necessary.
なんで！？
Why...?!
この戦争は　もう
お前を守るだけのものじゃ→
This is no longer just
a war to protect you.
ないんじゃぜ。
雷遁の瞬身に溶遁の血継限界か。
Lightning Style teleportation
and Lava Style Kekkei Genkai...
攻めは　なかなかだが…。
Impressive attacks...
溶けにくい男は　好きなんだけど
あなたは遠慮したいわね。
I usually like men
who are hard to melt...
But you, I want to avoid.
わしのスピードでもガードしてくる。
He counters me even
with my speed.
もっとスピードを…
ガードを崩すパワーを上げねば。
More speed... I need to increase
my power to crush his defense!
守りはどうだ？
What about your defense?
岩のゴーレムに砂の盾。
A Stone Golem and a Sand Shield...
この戦争はもう
みなで守りあう戦いじゃぜ。
This war is now a battle
to protect each other!
なら　俺だってここでマダラを…！
Then, I wanna fight Madara too!
砂と岩の二重防壁か。
A two-fold defensive wall of
Sand and Stone, huh?
これも　なかなかだな。
Also, quite impressive!
来るぞ！　ここからは攻めに回る！
Here he comes!
Time to go on the offensive!
水影　雷影　耳を貸せ。
Mizukage! Raikage!
Listen to me now!
待て！
Why you...! Hold it!
しつこいな。
How pesky!
よし　わかった！
All right. Understood!
水影！
Mizukage!
Water Style: Hidden Mist Jutsu!
《水遁　霧隠れの術！》
《霧隠れ…　これで輪廻眼の
視界を鈍らせるつもりですね》
Hidden Mist...
They're trying to weaken
the Rinnegan's field of vision with it.
やるぜ　雷影！
おう！
Let's do this, Raikage!
Right!
《土影め…　雷影自身を軽くして
更に　スピードアップしたか。
That Tsuchikage...
He lightened the Raikage
to increase his speed...
だが　それだと…》
However...
((軽いパンチだね))
Your punch is light.
あのときと同じだ。
気にすることは…。
It's just like the last time.
No need to worry...
超　加重岩の術！
Super Weighted Boulder Jutsu!
ばあちゃん　今のうちに俺を！
Granny, fix me up now!
聞け　ナルト。
Listen to me, Naruto...
わしはな　今回　この戦争→
You see... This war we're fighting...
初めは　ただ暁を倒すため→
In the beginning, I only agreed
to join the Allied Forces
しかたなく手を組み
忍連合にのった。
to get rid of the Akatsuki.
…が　お前たちとともに戦い→
But as I fought alongside you all,
前と違う感情を感じとる。
I started feeling differently.
今わしは　忍連合の土影として
ここにいたいのだ。
So now, I want to be here
as the Tsuchikage of
the Allied Shinobi Forces!
そして同じように→
In the same manner,
かつてバラバラだった忍の里々も
連合として一つとなり→
shinobi villages that were once
at odds have joined together,
変わろうとしている。
are changing and becoming one!
ならば　憎しみを生んできた
忍の世のシステムだって→
So maybe, this system of
the shinobi world
which has bred so much hatred
can change!
もしかしたら変われるかもしれん。
ナルト　こっちのマダラは
わしらに任せい。
Naruto...
Let us deal with this Madara!
必ずケリをつける。
I swear we shall settle this
once and for all!
それが　これまでの憎しみの
呪いを止める第一歩となる。
It will be our first step
in stopping the curse of hatred
we've been under until now!
マダラと同じように→
Like Madara, we are similarly guilty
of stirring up hatred in the past.
かつて憎しみを生み出してきた
わしらには→
そうしなければならない
責任がある。
It is our responsibility
to make things right!
ここは安心して　わしらに任せろ。
Rest assured and leave this to us!
じゃから
あっちのマダラは　お前に任せる。
So...
You go take care of
the other Madara!
それが　これからの希望を進める
第一歩となる。
That will become the first step
in promoting hope for the future.
古いヤツ　新しいヤツ
どちらのマダラにも勝つことが→
Old one, new one...
Defeating both Madaras
will bring an end to this war!
この戦争の終わりを意味する。
私たちは　この戦場で　お前を守る。
We will protect you on this battlefield!
だから　お前も向こうで戦い
私たちを守れ！
So protect us by fighting over there!
分身ナルト　お前に五影から
この言葉を預ける。
Clone Naruto... I entrust you with
this message from the Five Kage.
（みんな）勝つぞ！
We will win!
うん！
Yeah!
ぜってぇ勝つ！
We'll win!
let's keep walking
itsuka kitto kitto tadori tsuku tame ni
so we'll be sure to get there someday
ima wa madamada arukou
when I was young, I had a guitar as a toy
osanai koro te ni shita omocha kawaridatta gitaa
we just made noises, but that was enough to keep me engrossed
tada otowodasu hontou soredakeni muchu ni natte ita
giving up seems simple, but it's incredibly difficult
akirameru no wa kantan na youde ichiban muzukashii
I'll start singing today too
sousa boku wa kyou mo utau yo
I believe that my dream will come true I want to believe
dakara sou yume wa kanau shinjitai shinjitai
if I reach even one person
tatta hitori demo todoite kuretara
until I lose my voice
kono koe kareru made
I believe that everyone's dream can come true, I want to believe
dare demo yume wa kanau shinjiteru shinjiteru
the future is sure to change to a color you like better
dakara motto motto mirai wa korekara sukinairo ni kawaru yo
let's hold on to our dreams
yume wo daite arukou
Damn, it's so hard...
I couldn't even put a crack in it.
Chill out, Naruto...
Fool, ya fool.
I could've let him pass through me...
But he couldn't even damage this mask...
I hope that's not all the power you can
muster to control the Nine Tails.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Unbreakable Mask and the Shattered Bubble"
This jutsu... This chakra is...?